There are no clear answers to the question of why we dream, but there are different theories.
关于人为什么会做梦，目前尚无定论，但学界存在多种理论。
Dreaming is extraordinary and strange: you hallucinate, believe impossible things, and people you know may merge into one another.
梦境离奇而玄妙：你会产生幻觉，相信一些不可能发生的事，认识的人会与梦境融为一体。
And then, to top it off, you will likely forget all about it.
除此之外，醒来后你很可能会将这一切忘得一干二净。
Memory storage could be one reason for why we dream.
记忆储存可能是做梦的原因之一。
When you are asleep, the brain decides what information you should move to your long-term memory and what should be unlearnt.
人处于睡眠状态时，大脑会筛选信息，决定哪些内容要转入长期记忆，哪些内容可以被遗忘。
In a TED Talk, psychologist Amy Adkins described a 2010 experiment involving participants studying how to get out of a complex 3D maze. It was found that they were much better at attempting it if they had had a nap and dreamt of the maze.
心理学家埃米·阿德金斯在一场TED演讲中提到了2010年的一项实验：研究人员让参与者学习如何走出一个复杂的三维迷宫，结果发现，那些小憩时梦到迷宫的人，再次尝试走迷宫时表现要出色得多。
Another purpose of dreams could be the processing of our daily emotions, which may add to emotional memory consolidation.
做梦的另一个作用可能是处理日常情绪，这有助于情绪记忆的巩固。
In 2003, the Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience published research that experimented with the idea of dreams being a replication of our daily lives.
2003年，《认知神经科学杂志》刊登了一项研究，旨在验证“梦境是日常生活复现”这一观点。
Diary entries and dream journals of 29 healthy young adults over a two-week period were compared, and it was discovered that emotional themes from the day were replicated in dreams 35-55% of the time.
研究人员对比了29名健康年轻人两周内的日记与梦境记录，发现日间的情绪主题在梦境中复现的概率为35%至55%。
Antti Revonsuo, a Finnish scientist, has suggested that dreaming helps us to prepare for and deal with stressful situations.
芬兰科学家安蒂·雷翁苏奥提出，做梦能帮助我们为应对压力情境做好准备。
He studied children’s nightmares, giving an example of being continuously chased by wolves.
他研究了儿童的噩梦，比如梦到被狼群持续追赶的场景。
He believes dreams like this stem from our ancestors and could be a rehearsal for daily struggle and survival.
他认为这类梦境源于人类的祖先，是对日常生存斗争的预演。
In modern times, dreams and nightmares may be preparing us for social situations such as having a fight with a friend, going on a date or having a job interview.
在现代社会，梦境（包括噩梦）则可能是在帮我们预演各类社交场景，比如和朋友吵架、约会或是参加求职面试。
With such a variety of theories on why we dream, it seems that more research is needed before we can completely understand their purpose.
关于人为什么会做梦，理论层出不穷。貌似要想彻底弄清梦境的意义，我们还需要开展更多的研究。